The first thing we're going to learn about our templates and templates are really important to web programming.
Templates allow us to personalize web pages for the user.
And we're going to devote the first folders here of code 0 2 3 0 12 to understanding how templates work
with Go programming.
And there are some nuances to the standard library where you know for a lot of individuals if they try
to learn template straight from the standard library it's a struggle for them and it's hard for them
to figure out.
But I'm going to show you and have code resources to show you how to use templates using go.
I'm going to explain to you all of the nuances and so we'll see how to use functions pass functions
into templates how to pass data into templates how to access the data how a range or loop over data
inside of our templates.
And yes that's what we're going to see in a lot of hands on examples for you to practice like using
templates and passing data into templates and accessing that data and then templates will also see how
to abstract and modularize our code so we get you know take a page and break it into different parts
and then bring it back together.
And so I'm going to show you how to use nested templates.
And that's something else you're going to see as we work through templates.
Just a general understanding and definition of what templates are in case there's people out there and
this is like Hey I'm just getting started with webdav and it's your first time through and you've taken
the Go programming course and you're like OK how do I do webdav.
So template is like a form letter.
And in the in the sense that you have a generic letter like down here I have a generic letter right.
And this generic letter is going to be customized or personalized for every user in a database.
And so when I run a little program it will take for each user put their name there and then print the
ladder.
And so what comes out is something like this.
And when we use templates and web programming that's how we get personalized pages we create one page
and we say hey in this area put the user's profile in this area bring down the user's account information
and show the account information for that one user.
And so we're pulling that data out of a database and showing it on the template.
In standard library we have two packages we have text template and we also have each team template and
so text template lays the foundation for templates HVM template is everything which text template is.
And some additional functionality for doing each female pages.
Right so it has a lot of safety for preventing.
You know web attacks and cross-site scripting and things like that so it escapes a lot of characters
I've put together read me files at the beginning.
Right so if you look at our code base and we look through folders 0 2 3 0 12 there's a read we filed
the beginning of each of those folders like here is understanding templates and then techniques will
learn and code will use from the standard library write and type template and parsing templates.
And so for each folder there's little read me kind of showing you the highlights of what you should
get out of this section so you can look through each of these read.
And he kind of picked out like these are the things I need to know.
Or are you going to follow me through all of the videos and step through each one and explain them.