So this sounds like a little bit of an odd statement but and when you program with go one of my philosophies
one of my philosophies about go is go really encourages you to think like a programmer.
And that sounds like an odd statement because you know when you you know so many people use things like
peach pea or Ruby or Django with Python or Noad or whatever.
Right.
And they are doing programming but they might not necessarily be thinking like a programmer.
And so they might rely on a bunch of code word that's abstracted away functionality and they just use
some method and that's the way they get stuff done.
And so go really encourages you to approach the problem.
This is my perspective and see if there's a programmatic solution to it.
Like how would you use these programming tools to create the solution.
And that's what we'll be doing in this course.
We will eventually get to the point where we see hey here is here are these you know functions have
been written for us which we can use or this package which we can use which really simplifies a lot
of things for us and that's great but we're also going to look at problems from the programmers perspective
like how would we solve this with just programming.
So we're going to do that with templates.
And when we get to servers we're going to do that with servers right.
There's an entire package built for serving files and that's what we'll ultimately use.
But just for your own edification and so that you have a good knowledge base about how the web works
we're going to build our own TCAP server using the net package and HTP is a protocol that uses TCAP
server to do all the network transport's stuff and so it will build up our own network server in the
now allows us to understand you know multiplexers and routing and all of that and then we'll have some
insight into the functions that we end up using that abstract all that code in a Google level way for
us.
But we will build it up at a rudimentary level the exact same stuff.
So thinking like a programmer that's what go encourages And is there a programmatic solution to a problem
instead of just relying upon some library code that's already been written for you.
To that end when it comes to templating advised ask you that question.
Is there some way that you could just work with text and create merge data with an H UML file and get
an h m l filed come out as a programmer from a programmer's perspective.
Right you need to create an email file with that emerged into it.
How will you go about doing that.
So if we have and here's a solution maybe you want to pause a video and work on that for a second you
yourself just think it through.
But if we have you know just text we're working with strings we can use concatenate.
I can't say that word we can have an eight together strings to create what we want to do.
And so that's what these first three examples show.
And so I just call it rudimentary templating.
Right.
And so are primitive templating.
So here I have a string Todman cloud.
And then here I have a string and HD M-L document and I'm just merging this value with that value.
And then I'm printing it out.
And so that will print out the shemale text and if I change up folder here and go there there's my email
and I can also do government run and I go and I could dump that file using command line stuff like command
line commands and that's going to take the output pipe line the output of this and put it into that
file.
And so if I do that then I have an HMO shemale file and I could choose reveal and finder except I'm
on Windows and my Mac has Windows machines set up for recording show and explores what I'm looking for
and I could open that browser and there's my web page.
So just using BASIC programming I was able to merge data with an H email page and get that output so
mentally that you could do that.
And we could also you know approach that where Stabb using dumping to standard out.
We could do the same thing merge data with a string and then we could create a file using create from
the standard libraries OS package get our new file check the air write defer close the file and then
use IO copy and bring that string.
Make it a reader so he could pass it into IO copy.
So copy takes a reader and a writer writes strings new reader pass that string in and write to the new
file and will produce the file and then one last way we could do is we can accept arguments at the command
line and so from package OS we have args and I'm saying give me one and that's the name the first one
is the program you've executed the second one will be additional input and then you know concatenate
that data together with a string which is an email file.
Create a file and then write that file.
And so when we were run this last one here it was three go to Maine go to actually not like that.
And so there it is and it dumps that out.
And I can reveal that and show and explore.
And there you go.
McLeod and Page sors.
And there's my age you know.
So that's kind of a cool thing and I like that approach of just like think about it like a programmer.
How do we solve this problem we need to merge data with text.
And so these are some basic approaches at primitive low level rudimentary level to doing some templating
merging data with text because each email files are just text.
All right.
So in the next one we're going to take a look at next video.
Take a look at using a template parse file so from the text template package we have parsed files and
so we could start to do additional functionality which makes things easier.