So now we're going to start learning about the package text template from the standard library.
And we're going to begin our exploration and the next step in our learning about templates by reflecting
back upon the code in that previous example in 0 0 3 and there is a lot of issues with these.
This code right.
Like one of the issues is that it's all and package main and it's all in fun kumain.
So we'd want to do something to abstract that code to make it more reusable.
And one of the ways that we could do that is we could take all of this text right ear and we could put
it somewhere else we could get it out of Maine.
And so the best way to do this would be to have all for each html files as files and then to somehow
be able to bring them into our program and use them.
And so that's exactly what we're going to do in this next example and we're going to start learning
about the functions in the text template package from the standard library we're going start learning
about the functions in text template to be able to bring files into our program and use them.
And that's called parsing parsing a file.
So we'll have a bunch of files and we'll be able to parse them and then bring them into our program
and use them.
And we're going to start out with just one file.
So here I have a file TPL Diago each DML and that's where all that text is.
I'm not going to merge data with it yet because we're just going to learn this one step at a time.
But here is the first step is to be able to you know abstract our code be able to bring the text of
the files that we want out into separate files and then bring those into our program and use them by
parsing them.
And so that's the first step is to abstract it get that text into its own file and bring him into our
program and use him.
We're not going to merge data and yet we will do that very soon.
All right.
So here I have TPL Diago HD M-L and you can see the extension that go each DMO.
So that's the customary extension used with Go programming but this is not like ph P or Espey or cold
fusion.
See if them if you go back far enough right.
It's not like you have to have that file extension because these are just files and we're going to tell
our program to Hey go get those files and bring them in so we can name these files anything we want.
Right.
I could call this
the great north west as an extension and call it GMR for grandma or I could call it HP if I wanted or
I could call it ph be SPCS them whatever extension I wanted to call it I could call it but the customary
traditional extension for Go programming is go each humoral.
And when we serve our files we'll be serving them right from a restful when we serve them in a restful
way.
And so the file extension is not going to matter and it's just code within our program that our program
uses.
All right.
So that's the file extension that's traditionally used go each Jamail and you could use whatever you
like but that's the customary one to use.
So what we'll do is we will parse this file and then we'll be able to use that file and we can execute
it and we can execute it to some location right.
This takes writer interface takes typewriter says all we do.
So to understand how we parse files and bring them into our program it's good for us to go look at the
text template package from the standard library and I want to go down to the index and I want to explore
that.
So we go to the index we can see here at the index for text template we have a type template and type
template has it CAN'T ZOOM IN ON THIS.
That's disappointing to me.
I wish I could zoom in type template has parse files and parse glob and then also new and must and I'll
explain what these these do here.
And then we when we parse files we get a pointer to a template.
If we parse a glob we get a pointer to a template.
If we use new we get a pointer to template we use must we get a pointer to a template.
So if we use any of these functions we get a pointer to a template and this is type template and if
we have a pointer to a template we have all of these methods available to us.
Right.
All these different methods are attached to any value which is of type A pointer to a template.
So some of those methods are a parse parse files and parse Glubb interesting writes parse files and
parse glob down here and parse files and parse glob of here.
So the way I want you to think of a pointer to a template it's a container into which all of your templates
get parsed and are held.
So pointer to a template is a container.
This is just Todd's definition of it is a container into which all of the templates get parsed and are
held.
So let me show you how this works and then I'll come back to that.
The standard library to make sure we understand the functionality.
So when we read our code we're reading this Daut notation is package and then function or type right.
Is the next thing so from package template.
We're going to use parse files and this is from text template.
Be careful when you use your autocomplete.
If it says each tim template you're using a different package and that's going to give you a different
result.
So if your code is looking different it might be because you have text him H.M. Templeton's that text
template.
We're just going to start out with a text template at first and then we will move up Tahj female template
after we understand how text template is working.
So from package template I parse files I give it the file name right and if I look at what parse files
does parse files to is a very adek parameter where it takes zero or more strings.
Right.
So if I wanted to I could pass in as many filenames here as I wanted so I could do you know to be able
to decode each D-Mo. if I had it so I could just keep asking filenames in there.
And so it's going to parse those and then it's going to store them parse files gives me back a pointer
to a template and in there.
So I checked my air and I have my pointer to a template and remember the way I want you to think about
a pointer to a template is a container which is holding all of the templates which I've parsed.
OK.
Container holding all the templates which I parse Zagat say template execute and execute once execute.
It takes a writer and data.
OK.
And so I'm executing the standard out which implements the writer interface and I am passing in no data.
All right.
So this is going to execute to standard out.
Let's just watch Iran because that will help you see what's happening.
Change.
Change is for one I.
So there it parse that template.
Right.
And then I executed my template to standard.
And I was able to see that pretty cool.
Additionally if I wanted to we're just parsing one file here I could also write parse my files get my
pointer to a template which is a container holding all the files I parsed in this case have only parsed
one and I could create a new file and then I could execute my template and I could pass the new file
in there it's a new file template.
Execute X-C employee request template execute requests a writer right.
And it also takes doubt and we're not passing in any data some doing nil.
But since a file implements the rider interface I can now pass a new file in there and template execute
will write the results to this new file indexed Cudicini.
And so can go into that directory and go and it ran.
And then I'll see index studies you know all right there and it put it all in indexed on each mail.
So the two steps here are part of your files and then execute your files.
And if we look at the standard library we can see that once we parse files we get a pointer to a template
and when we have a pointer to a template we have execute.
OK.
So that method execute is right there.
Taschen 10 template we get a value of type pointer to a template that now has the method execute attached
to it which we can do execute takes a writer and data.
And here we're doing a new file to write to so that's that's using parse files.
And here we're doing parse files template parts files and we're just parsing one file but then down
here we do TPL parse files.
So when I get a value of type template pointer to a template.
Right that's a container which holds all of the templates I've parsed.
OK.
And all if I one of them if I then later decide where I want to add some more templates into that container.
Well here's my container.
It's a type pointer to a template.
And if I go look at the standard library type pointer to template as all these methods.
One of the methods is parse files.
Right.
So now that I have a value which is my TVL of type pointer to a template I have a method attached to
it.
Parse files which allows me to add more files into my value of type pointer to a template which I've
told you to think about as a container holding your templates and so here I parse one file and then
I execute that one file to standard out.
And then I parse two more files into my value of type pointer to template my container which holds all
of my templates and now instead of just execute I'm going to specify execute template.
So down here in this library right we have both execute which takes a writer and data or we have execute
template which takes a writer name and data and so execute template allows me to execute a specific
template.
So if my container which holds all of my templates this TPL variable right if it has more than if it
only has one template I could just say template execute.
But if it has more than one template I want to specify which template.
So I use execute template and I say to standard out execute this template execute this template execute
that template.
And so if I run that and I'm in a three
right I get one back to 1 1.
So one Mesbah to one and then down here I ran execute again and execute just executes whatever's the
first one it finds in the container.
So I found one first maybe because that's the first one I put in.
So generally speaking and what we're going to use in this course is we're always going to use execute
template just so that we can be specific about which template we are executing.
And instead of using parse files which you have to list all of your files that you want to parse then
we are going to use parse glob because in the standard library we have we could parse files and we can
give all the file names or we could parse glob.
So if you've done any Unix stuff you know glob is just like a big.
Basically what it sounds glob of stuff.
Right.
And and so glob here is a folder and we're going to do template parse Glaum and we're going to look
in this folder and we're going to parse any file that has this extension GMH.
Alternatively I can just say give me all of the files in that folder.
Right.
And so I gave a GM show just to show you that we could call it anything but just to be compliant with
the standards you know not the standards but the customary ways of programming.
And then to call call this go HVM Mal here is stand customs.
All right.
Go east you know and then I'll change all these HMO.
There you go.
So I'm going to parse the glob.
Who's going to parse all my templates in this folder.
I've got one.
I've got to I've got Vosper.
Just so you could see that they could be called anything.
And and then I'm going to ask you see which one comes out just how curiosity.
And then I'm going to use execute template to execute specifically a certain template.
And so that's 0 for.
And I have one Vesper's to one.
So one was the first one that got executed.
Maybe it does it alphabetically I don't know.
And then we are best to on.
And those are specifically you know which ones.
So one last thing we could do with our templates to make sure that our programs perform it is we want
to make sure that we parse all of our templates only once again I'm just going to change these two GMH
are to go HMO.
There we go.
I'm just going to say do everything in that folder and then I need to update each of these
go.
And so now to make this performant only want to parse my templates once so I'm going to use funkin net
which initializes my program.
It runs once when the program is starting up.
And so when my program starts up I'm going to parse this whole glob.
Right.
And I'm going to store that in my TPL variable which is of type pointer to template from package template.
What's this template must function doing right there.
So if we can go back and look at the standard library the documentation for package text template we
see that when we parse glob we get back a pointer to a template and then there right.
And here must takes a pointer to a template and an air and returns just a template.
Right so must is going to do my error checking for me.
If I go and I look at Must I see that must right.
Does my error checking and then returns the template.
So I could use mice to avoid doing my or my error checking so I could use parse glob it gives me a pointer
to a template in there.
You know parse glob gives me a pointer to Templin in there right.
That gives me a pointer to template in there right there.
And and and must takes a pointer to a template and then there.
So what parse glob returns is exactly what must takes so parse glob runs returns a pointer to implement
and there must now has a pointer to a template in there and it returns a template which I sign right
there.
And I put this up here at this level.
So it's at package level the scope that way TPL is accessible through out this package.
And then I execute my templates so exactly the same thing same output.
But let's just see a run
and same stuff.
So that's how we work with templates and go right that's text template and the two main steps you want
to do is you want to parse glob.
So get all of your templates and store them into a variable of type pointer to a template and you can
think of that variable right.
That's this TPL right here.
And you can call that whatever you want that's just an identifier.
You can think of that variable as a container holding all of the templates which you've parsed and and
then you can execute those templates so execute to this writer this template and I'm not passing in
data.
All right.
So I hope that's clear and what we're going to use in this course is we're going to use this structure
right here right where we're parsing glob and then we're going to use execute template.
But I just want to make sure you saw the standard library and how those different pieces work together.
Cool.
We're on our way.