So now we're going to pass data into our template.
But before we do that I just want to take a second to review what we saw in the last video and now is
all about parsing our files and then executing him so parse and execute just ingrain that in your head.
That's what you want to do.
Want to parse all my templates and then execute a template and we're going to use parts glob and execute
template to do that.
But I've just pulled out some of the functions which I think are the highlights from the text template
package.
And so here's a type template and again you read that.
So some people look at that students look at that and get the doublespeak like what template template
programming is crazy.
But this is package and this is like some type or some function or variable.
And so here we have package template type template.
And then what we do is we parse and then we execute.
And for parsing we'll be using parse glob.
And that gives us a pointer to a template but there's also parse files up at the top package level.
And once we have a value of type pointer to template we can add more files into our container that value
of type pointer to a template and we can do that with parse parse files or parts glob.
Right.
So we also have those methods attached to a value of type pointer to a template and then we we execute
our templates and we could use execute or execute template and this course will be using execute template
with parse glob.
Right.
And we'll be doing that by using the helper function template must which just gives us back the pointer
template and then also the net function.
All right cool sets a little bit very view.
But now we're going to learn how to pass data into our templates and how we get that data to display
once we pass it in.
So the syntax for displaying data is just that his curly braces to curly braces to curly braces and
then the data is a dot.
And so the dot might seem kind of strange when you know depending upon where you're coming from but
the door is the current value of the data at that point in execution.
And so if I've just passed in a piece of data it's that data that I've just passed in and if that data
happened to be a slice and I was arranging over the slice then as I range over the slice the output
of that range would become the new input of the next field and we'll see that in action.
But for now the dot is the current piece of data and the current piece of data is whatever I passed.
So what am I passing in in this program instead of having nil which I had before.
Right.
I'm now going to pass in 42 which is the answer to the meaning of life the meaning of life is 42.
And so yes so 42 got passed into my template.
Let's watch her on
the meaning of life is 42.
Cool.
And so that's it.
You want to pass that and you pass it in right there and you only get a pass in one piece of data so
that trips people out a little bit.
Like what.
Wait How's that work.
If you're coming from other server side programming but you pass in one piece of data.
But fortunately we can pass in a piece of data which is aggregate data type.
Right.
So it's agrah aggregate data structure.
So we can pass in a struct which has a whole bunch of fields and those fields could be you know of values
of type map or type slice or of type another struct.
And so really we can pass in as much as we want but you only get a pass in one piece of data or data
structure and then you get access that when you get into your template.
So that's how you pass data into a template.