So now we're going to learn how to assign a value to a variable in a template and that looks like this.
All right so here's my template and here is the value which I've passed into my template I'm taking
that value and using the short declaration.
Operator I'm assigning it to a variable in my template and so those of you who are coming from PH are
going to feel happy that you use dollar signs to access our variables again.
Right.
But I assign that value to a variable and now I can access that variable anywhere on my template and
display its value right.
So that comes in handy sometimes.
It's good to know about I just wanted to point it out and show you this is how you do it.
And this is the exact same file that we saw in the previous video in the previous example except I've
changed the data that's being passed down.
I'm passing in a string here instead of an int and and I Severgnini is parse Glubb throughout the course.
And you notice I'm using parse files.
But hopefully after looking at that two videos back about parsing and executing templates parsing and
executing files hopefully you see from the standard library how that all works because template parse
files or template parse glob both give me back a value a pointer to a template a value of type pointer
to a template and an heir by using must.
So I don't have to check that Arutz checking it for me that I get my TBO and execute template and I
specify the template I'm executing.
So I'm just using parse files because we're only parsing one file and I don't have a folder.
So anyhow that's when I'm passing And so when I run this because the proof is in the pudding.
You talk about cooking all day long but unless you cook something that I cannot talk and type apparently
at the same time.
Yeah right.
So I'll talk unless you're actually cooking stuff that tastes good.
Cool.
There you go.
So I passed on the meaning of life release self-focus embrace other focus.
So that's it.
I passed in the data.
Right.
And I took that value and I signed it to a variable and I printed that variable out.